<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Frame on Furbuild</title>
    <link>http://furbuild.com/tags/frame/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Frame on Furbuild</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-gb</language>
    <copyright>All rights reserved - 2015</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 07 Feb 2016 22:19:51 +0100</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://furbuild.com/tags/frame/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Elastic band head frame</title>
      <link>http://furbuild.com/post/elastic-band-head-frame/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 07 Feb 2016 22:19:51 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://furbuild.com/post/elastic-band-head-frame/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;In our planning process we talked about what qualities we value the most in suit heads.
We listed a few good qualities and picked the ones that matter the most to us in order to decide how we wanted to make the head.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We wanted smaller, streamlined suit heads, entirely made out of foam.
We also wanted the heads to have a movable jaw, so it was important that our design included this mechanism.
The base we settled on was several elastic bands sewn together.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&#34;design-for-style-comfort:0b727e6627b744564d71dfd66ab2a78d&#34;&gt;Design for style &amp;amp; comfort&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We used three elastic bands.
A thick band going around the skull.
Two smaller bands connected to the big band, one going over and one going under the chin to form a comfortable mount.
The frame ended up as a very snug, comfortable fit with the by-product of being able to attach a movable jaw.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://furbuild.com/images/head-frames-front-and-profile.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Head frames from the front &amp;amp; profile&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&#34;design-for-hygiene:0b727e6627b744564d71dfd66ab2a78d&#34;&gt;Design for hygiene&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Suiting is sweaty business, so we made sure a balaclava can be swiftly replaced with another one out on the field.
The mount is in no way attached to the balaclava and could in essentially be worn without one, though I wouldn&amp;rsquo;t recommend it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://furbuild.com/images/head-frame-loose.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Loose head frame without balaclava&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&#34;design-for-accessibility-longevity:0b727e6627b744564d71dfd66ab2a78d&#34;&gt;Design for accessibility &amp;amp; longevity&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Out in the field it&amp;rsquo;s great if you can stop to rest and take off the head, and we didn&amp;rsquo;t want the act to cause too much damage to the head.
We decided to make the frame open from the back, using snap fasteners to connect the sides.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://furbuild.com/images/head-frame-unbuttoned.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Buttons at the back of a head frame&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&#34;results:0b727e6627b744564d71dfd66ab2a78d&#34;&gt;Results&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We&amp;rsquo;ve been wearing the head frames with balaclavas underneath for a few hours without any problems.
It&amp;rsquo;s very comfortable, excited to see how it feels when we&amp;rsquo;ve attached the foam to the frame.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Each frame took about &lt;strong&gt;3 hours&lt;/strong&gt; to make, from measuring to sewing by hand.
The material cost for both was 288 SEK (38 USD), including the balaclavas, elastic band and thread.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>