<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts on Furbuild</title>
    <link>http://furbuild.com/post/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Posts on Furbuild</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-gb</language>
    <copyright>All rights reserved - 2015</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 14 Feb 2016 20:35:00 +0100</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://furbuild.com/post/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Working with foam</title>
      <link>http://furbuild.com/post/working-with-foam/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 14 Feb 2016 20:35:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://furbuild.com/post/working-with-foam/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;Continuing from &lt;a href=&#34;http://furbuild.com/post/designing-and-measuring-heads&#34;&gt;my theoretical post about designing heads&lt;/a&gt;, at this point things got a bit experimental.
Having no prior experience in building fursuit heads, and wanting to do things our own way meant that our best bet was to take a trial-and-error approach with a lot of margin.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&#34;starting-with-the-jaw:a6c0bbd6f8887a2bde084e98653193a0&#34;&gt;Starting with the jaw&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I plotted out the rough foam shape that I thought I would need and added a centimeter or two on all sides to make sure that I would have enough to work with.
I figured it would be easier to cut away excess foam than to add more.
The images below show the plotting out of the rough shape and what it translated to in real life.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://furbuild.com/images/sketch-stylized-caraid-foam-layer.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Digital sketch of the shape&#34; /&gt;
&lt;img src=&#34;http://furbuild.com/images/foam-jaw-cutout.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Foam jaw cut-out&#34; /&gt;
&lt;img src=&#34;http://furbuild.com/images/foam-jaw-gluing.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Gluing foam jaw&#34; /&gt;
&lt;img src=&#34;http://furbuild.com/images/foam-jaw-glued.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Glued foam jaw&#34; /&gt;
&lt;img src=&#34;http://furbuild.com/images/foam-jaw-mounted.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Mounted foam jaw&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&#34;the-satisfaction-of-sculpting:a6c0bbd6f8887a2bde084e98653193a0&#34;&gt;The satisfaction of sculpting&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After having cut out the rough foam shape and glued it onto the elastic straps, I could start the sculpting of the lower jaw.
This was an entirely new experience for me, using simple box cutters to chip away at the foam until it had the desired shape.
It took a bit of time getting used to, but after half an hour or so I got more and more confident, cutting away larger chunks and being fairly happy with the direction it was going.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://furbuild.com/images/foam-jaw-sculpted.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Sculped foam jaw&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We applied the same method for the muzzle, though this time I did not strictly follow the sketch I made and instead relied on my knowledge of the feline head structure to sculpt more intuitively.
I used a sharpie to draw directly onto the foam cut-out and so created guidelines for myself to cut around.
I then copied these guidelines over to the other side of the face to try and maintain some symmetry - this didn&amp;rsquo;t always turn out quite as planned, and for future reference I would not remove the head from the mannequin during the carving process to ensure that everything remains aligned.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://furbuild.com/images/foam-muzzle-cutout.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Paper muzzle cut-out&#34; /&gt;
&lt;img src=&#34;http://furbuild.com/images/foam-muzzle-pieces.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Foam pieces for the muzzle&#34; /&gt;
&lt;img src=&#34;http://furbuild.com/images/foam-muzzle-sculpted.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Work in progress of the muzzle sculpt&#34; /&gt;
&lt;img src=&#34;http://furbuild.com/images/foam-muzzle-finished.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;the finished muzzle carving&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For the top of the head and the nose bridge, we did not refer to the sketch at all but simply cut out a rectangular shape, covering all of the top of the head and muzzle so that I could carve out the head shape that I wanted.
For this we had to remove the initial &amp;ldquo;helmet&amp;rdquo; we had, which was not quite big enough.
I drew a center line over the top of the head and sketched out the rough structure of the top of the muzzle to make sure everything would be aligned and in proportion.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://furbuild.com/images/foam-head-top-glued.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Rectangular cover on top of the head&#34; /&gt;
&lt;img src=&#34;http://furbuild.com/images/foam-head-top-line-drawing.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Sketching out the top of the head&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;From here on everything was done &lt;em&gt;&amp;ldquo;wing it&amp;rdquo;-style&lt;/em&gt;.
For the eyebrows I simply cut out shapes I thought I needed, glued it on top of the base and carved out the shapes I wanted.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://furbuild.com/images/foam-eyebrows-glued.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Rough eyebrows glued onto base&#34; /&gt;
&lt;img src=&#34;http://furbuild.com/images/foam-eyebrows-sculpted.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Sculpted eyebrows&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For the ears I took a slightly more elaborate approach - sadly I forgot to take pictures of the process, but I&amp;rsquo;ll try to summarize what I did.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I cut a basic ear shape out of paper, curved it around and pinned it onto the head in the rough position I wanted them to be in.
I then cut away at the base and the shape of the paper until I was satisfied with the way it sat on the head and how it looked (roughly) from the front, side and back, bearing in mind that I could add thickness with the foam.
I then took the resulting paper cutout, traced it out on the thinnest foam we have and used that as the base shape of the ear.
Since ears are rounded at the base I wanted to add some thickness, so I cut out a piece of thicker foam to cover most of the ear shape and glued it on top of the thinner foam so I could carve away at it later.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://furbuild.com/images/rough-ear-shape.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Rough ear-shape&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, what I had now was an ear-shaped block of foam that I simply sculpted into the ear shape I wanted - using references of lionesses and other big cats as a guideline for the form.
Occasionally I would press it onto the head to see how it would sit and ensure that I would have space and surface to glue the two together.
Once I had one ear finished I repeated the process for the other, pinned them both onto the head and drew an outline around them to make sure that I would glue them in the right place.
Once glued on we noticed that they did not align perfectly, but it was easy enough to make some adjustments to fix the symmetry.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://furbuild.com/images/foam-ears-front.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Ears front&#34; /&gt;
&lt;img src=&#34;http://furbuild.com/images/foam-ears-front-profile.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Ears front profile&#34; /&gt;
&lt;img src=&#34;http://furbuild.com/images/foam-ears-profile.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Ears profile&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&#34;results-that-exceed-expectations:a6c0bbd6f8887a2bde084e98653193a0&#34;&gt;Results that exceed expectations&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I don&amp;rsquo;t know if our expectations were low, but the end results were very satisfying and far exceeded our expectation for our first prototype suit head.
I didn&amp;rsquo;t think the jaw was going to move as well as it did.
Just look at how excited Zee is.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote class=&#34;twitter-tweet&#34;&gt;&lt;p lang=&#34;en&#34; dir=&#34;ltr&#34;&gt;Our prototype lioness &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/hashtag/fursuit?src=hash&#34;&gt;#fursuit&lt;/a&gt; head has been sufficiently foamed! &lt;a href=&#34;https://t.co/g3rW00xBIZ&#34;&gt;https://t.co/g3rW00xBIZ&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&amp;mdash; Philip V. (Zee) (@zeeraw) &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/zeeraw/status/698889800120725504&#34;&gt;February 14, 2016&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;script async src=&#34;//platform.twitter.com/widgets.js&#34; charset=&#34;utf-8&#34;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Designing and measuring heads</title>
      <link>http://furbuild.com/post/designing-and-measuring-heads/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 14 Feb 2016 20:20:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://furbuild.com/post/designing-and-measuring-heads/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;Before we could begin with plotting out the foam to carve the prototype fursuit head, we needed a reference to work from.
Since we did not have our own mannequin heads yet, I looked up images of head bases in Google and found a convenient turnaround which I loaded in Photoshop and laid out in such a way that I could easily sketch over it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://furbuild.com/images/head-turnaround.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Convenient turnaround&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&#34;to-the-drawing-board:bd6efe38cf959a7fa683dd2331df3df2&#34;&gt;To the Drawing Board&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Since I am more familiar with &lt;a href=&#34;http://furbuild.com/character/caraid&#34;&gt;my own character&lt;/a&gt; I started with her.
Initially, we wanted to go for a more realistic approach but weren&amp;rsquo;t happy with the way it looked.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://furbuild.com/images/sketch-realistic-caraid.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Realistic Caraid sketch&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So instead, we went for slightly more stylized heads, with larger eyes, a more expressive face and slightly exaggerated proportions.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://furbuild.com/images/sketch-stylized-caraid.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Stylized Caraid sketch&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After having sketched out my own character, it was easy enough to translate the features and proportions onto &lt;a href=&#34;http://furbuild.com/character/zee&#34;&gt;Zee&amp;rsquo;s&lt;/a&gt; head.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://furbuild.com/images/sketch-stylized-zee.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Stylized Zee sketch&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While not relevant yet, I was curious to see what our characters would look like in color so I roughed in their colorations after having finished the sketches.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://furbuild.com/images/sketch-color-zee-cara.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Zee &amp;amp; Cara in color&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&#34;getting-the-measurements:bd6efe38cf959a7fa683dd2331df3df2&#34;&gt;Getting the measurements&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Obviously, the digital head I had in Photoshop and our mannequins were not of the same size, so to translate my sketches into real life measurements I had to calculate the ratio between the virtual head and the real one.
We did this by measuring the width of our mannequins at the widest part of the head, then measuring the width of the digital mannequin (Photoshop has a ruler tool which you can use for this).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While the exact measurements are not particularly relevant for this article, we found out that the digital head was &lt;code&gt;10cm&lt;/code&gt; wide, and the real one &lt;code&gt;19cm&lt;/code&gt;.
This meant that the ratio for all of the measurements was &lt;code&gt;1.9:1&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, all we had to do now was get the measurements of the sketch, multiply them by &lt;code&gt;1.9&lt;/code&gt; and we would have the real life measurements.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=YRL4uIVzVWI&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Yeah science!&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&#34;up-next:bd6efe38cf959a7fa683dd2331df3df2&#34;&gt;Up next!&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I am putting these concepts in to practice in my post about &lt;a href=&#34;http://furbuild.com/post/working-with-foam/&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Working with foam&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>First iteration of the frame</title>
      <link>http://furbuild.com/post/first-iteration-of-the-frame/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 14 Feb 2016 11:51:18 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://furbuild.com/post/first-iteration-of-the-frame/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://furbuild.com/post/elastic-band-head-frame/&#34;&gt;Our first design&lt;/a&gt; didn&amp;rsquo;t work out too well.
As we attached foam to the frame. it would stretch the elastic bands until a point where it wasn&amp;rsquo;t snug enough to support all that weight.
Top of the frame wasn&amp;rsquo;t solid enough to support large ears which would also become a problem.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We were able to go with an ad-hoc solution and extend the existing frame with two thicker elastic bands going over the top of the head.
Once attached, everything sat snugly, resting on top of the head and as a result the jaw got more animated as it was more closely connected.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://furbuild.com/images/head-frame-ad-hoc-fix.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Ad-hoc solution to the head we had already started to foam&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I took these learnings and preemptively improved the head frame that had not yet been foamed.
It&amp;rsquo;s pretty much same as the ad-hoc solution but much better fitted.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://furbuild.com/images/head-frame-mk-2-front-profile.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;MK2 front profile&#34; /&gt;
&lt;img src=&#34;http://furbuild.com/images/head-frame-mk-2-profile.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;MK2 profile&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We decided that there&amp;rsquo;s no point in being able to open up the head in the back.
Once the foam goes on the elastic bands it&amp;rsquo;s extremely easy to just pull it over your head.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://furbuild.com/images/head-frame-mk-2-back.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;MK2 back&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&#34;conclusion:e9e0af3b10ef50fb3440d0b8ffe7a28d&#34;&gt;Conclusion&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s much more comfortable than it was before since it distributes the weight on all of your head and not just around it.
I&amp;rsquo;m also very happy with how light yet sturdy it is.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Free sample fur swatches</title>
      <link>http://furbuild.com/post/free-sample-fur-swatches/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 09 Feb 2016 17:56:14 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://furbuild.com/post/free-sample-fur-swatches/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;I found a site called &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.fabric-online.co.uk/faux-fur-fabric?cat=17072&#34;&gt;&lt;em&gt;fabric-online&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; who provide up to four sample fur swatches.
We only payed the shipping cost of &lt;strong&gt;£4.80&lt;/strong&gt; from the UK to Sweden.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here are the samples we ordered and what we want to use respective type for:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&#34;ivory-shorthaired:cfbb93e52dd4ff45f532d449b6913704&#34;&gt;Ivory shorthaired&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Intended for &lt;a href=&#34;http://furbuild.com/character/caraid&#34;&gt;Cara&amp;rsquo;s&lt;/a&gt; muzzle, chin, throat and stomach.
&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.fabric-online.co.uk/ivory-shorthaired&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://furbuild.com/images/fur-ivory-shorthaired.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&#34;london-cream:cfbb93e52dd4ff45f532d449b6913704&#34;&gt;London cream&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Intended for &lt;a href=&#34;http://furbuild.com/character/caraid&#34;&gt;Cara&amp;rsquo;s&lt;/a&gt; chest and ears.
&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.fabric-online.co.uk/london-cream&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://furbuild.com/images/fur-london-cream.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&#34;london-brown:cfbb93e52dd4ff45f532d449b6913704&#34;&gt;London brown&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Intended for small details on &lt;a href=&#34;http://furbuild.com/character/caraid&#34;&gt;Cara&lt;/a&gt; and the majority of &lt;a href=&#34;http://furbuild.com/character/zee&#34;&gt;Zee&lt;/a&gt;&amp;rsquo;s coat.
&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.fabric-online.co.uk/london-brown&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://furbuild.com/images/fur-london-brown.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&#34;london-beige:cfbb93e52dd4ff45f532d449b6913704&#34;&gt;London beige&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Intended for some of &lt;a href=&#34;http://furbuild.com/character/zee&#34;&gt;Zee&lt;/a&gt;&amp;rsquo;s coat.
&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.fabric-online.co.uk/london-beige&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://furbuild.com/images/fur-london-beige.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ordering our first batch of foam</title>
      <link>http://furbuild.com/post/ordering-our-first-batch-of-foam/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 Feb 2016 18:13:23 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://furbuild.com/post/ordering-our-first-batch-of-foam/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;Today I ordered foam from a &lt;em&gt;foam specialist&lt;/em&gt; here in Sweden called &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.skumplastspecialisten.se/index.asp&#34;&gt;Skumplastspecialisten&lt;/a&gt;.
They will conveniently deliver the foam to a bed store next to my workplace.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Since I have no idea how much foam will be used, I have no idea if this is a generous or conservative order for two suit heads.
Considering the heads will be quite small, I assume we can be quite economical with the amount of foam.
I ended up ordering three pieces of foam, exaggerating slightly for my estimates.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;code&gt;50 * 50 * 5 cm&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; — Medium hard&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;code&gt;50 * 100 * 3 cm&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; — Medium hard&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;code&gt;50 * 50 * 2 cm&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; — Very hard&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&#34;options-in-quality:5760f0fd29bf802c85cfe12dc6f022cf&#34;&gt;Options in quality&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We had a variety in options of what foam to get, ranging in thickness, hardness and cell structure.
All the foam we ended up ordering was normal polyester foam.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&#34;costliness-of-specialist-foam:5760f0fd29bf802c85cfe12dc6f022cf&#34;&gt;Costliness of specialist foam&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The total price for the foam ended up on &lt;strong&gt;700 SEK (82.65 USD)&lt;/strong&gt; which was somewhat expected if we wanted specific types of foam.
I think the only cheaper option would have been to buy a foam mattress, but we decided against it.
We&amp;rsquo;re not paying any shipping cost since they&amp;rsquo;re constantly shipping large batches to the bed store.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&#34;inspiration:5760f0fd29bf802c85cfe12dc6f022cf&#34;&gt;Inspiration&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There is an abundance of resources on the interwebs for making fursuit heads with foam.
For most people, I think &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.matrices.net/foam.asp&#34;&gt;Matrices has the best rundown of the basics&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Then I&amp;rsquo;ve also found a very useful time-lapse of someone sculpting their head with foam. 
&lt;div style=&#34;position: relative; padding-bottom: 56.25%; padding-top: 30px; height: 0; overflow: hidden;&#34;&gt;
  &lt;iframe src=&#34;//www.youtube.com/embed/eRHyYimr3GI&#34; style=&#34;position: absolute; top: 0; left: 0; width: 100%; height: 100%;&#34; allowfullscreen frameborder=&#34;0&#34;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
 &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Elastic band head frame</title>
      <link>http://furbuild.com/post/elastic-band-head-frame/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 07 Feb 2016 22:19:51 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://furbuild.com/post/elastic-band-head-frame/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;In our planning process we talked about what qualities we value the most in suit heads.
We listed a few good qualities and picked the ones that matter the most to us in order to decide how we wanted to make the head.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We wanted smaller, streamlined suit heads, entirely made out of foam.
We also wanted the heads to have a movable jaw, so it was important that our design included this mechanism.
The base we settled on was several elastic bands sewn together.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&#34;design-for-style-comfort:0b727e6627b744564d71dfd66ab2a78d&#34;&gt;Design for style &amp;amp; comfort&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We used three elastic bands.
A thick band going around the skull.
Two smaller bands connected to the big band, one going over and one going under the chin to form a comfortable mount.
The frame ended up as a very snug, comfortable fit with the by-product of being able to attach a movable jaw.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://furbuild.com/images/head-frames-front-and-profile.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Head frames from the front &amp;amp; profile&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&#34;design-for-hygiene:0b727e6627b744564d71dfd66ab2a78d&#34;&gt;Design for hygiene&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Suiting is sweaty business, so we made sure a balaclava can be swiftly replaced with another one out on the field.
The mount is in no way attached to the balaclava and could in essentially be worn without one, though I wouldn&amp;rsquo;t recommend it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://furbuild.com/images/head-frame-loose.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Loose head frame without balaclava&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&#34;design-for-accessibility-longevity:0b727e6627b744564d71dfd66ab2a78d&#34;&gt;Design for accessibility &amp;amp; longevity&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Out in the field it&amp;rsquo;s great if you can stop to rest and take off the head, and we didn&amp;rsquo;t want the act to cause too much damage to the head.
We decided to make the frame open from the back, using snap fasteners to connect the sides.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://furbuild.com/images/head-frame-unbuttoned.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Buttons at the back of a head frame&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&#34;results:0b727e6627b744564d71dfd66ab2a78d&#34;&gt;Results&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We&amp;rsquo;ve been wearing the head frames with balaclavas underneath for a few hours without any problems.
It&amp;rsquo;s very comfortable, excited to see how it feels when we&amp;rsquo;ve attached the foam to the frame.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Each frame took about &lt;strong&gt;3 hours&lt;/strong&gt; to make, from measuring to sewing by hand.
The material cost for both was &lt;strong&gt;288 SEK (38 USD)&lt;/strong&gt;, including the balaclavas, elastic band and thread.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>